renewableenergyworld.com 2018-10-05

# Privacy Policy - PennWell Corporate

PennWell is committed to protecting your privacy.  We have procedures in place to ensure that we adhere to the latest privacy practices including adhering to U.S. state laws (California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance), Federal laws (CAN-SPAM, Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), International agreements (EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework), and International laws where applicable.

When you visit one of our websites or other digital services, we may collect anonymous or personally identifiable information from you. Personally identifiable information (PII) is information that can identify you, such as your full name, email address, postal address, telephone number, and fax number. In some cases, you may provide information to us, and in other cases information about you or your activities on our Services may be automatically collected.

When you provide information to us by registering on one of our websites subscribing to one of our newsletters, responding to a survey, filling out a form or voluntarily providing any other information across any of our digital services, we may choose to capture that information.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number or credit card information.

When you download or use apps created by us or our subsidiaries, we may receive information about your location, app usage and your mobile device.  We may use this information to provide you with location-based or other services.

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience
  * To improve our website
  * To process your orders or requests and to pre-populate forms
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To send periodic emails
  * To match the right messages to you on our sites or on third party sites
  * To offer you opportunities to connect directly with your peers and with sellers of technology or services that may be of interest to you
  * For any other purpose that we tell you about when you give us the information

We may process your personal information for our legitimate business interests, these include but are not limited to: fraud prevention, direct marketing, network and information systems security, data analytics or data enhancement, modifying or improving our services, identifying usage trends, and determining the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising. You have the right to object to this processing.

The information you provide will be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your subscription, order, download, or other transaction. In addition, you may receive related company news, updates, and product or service information, etc.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails from us, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email. You may also reach us via our [Customer Service Form](https://www.hubs.com/power/contact).

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information. We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be kept on file for more than 60 days.

Yes, we use cookies.  Cookies are small files that a site, or its service provider, transfers to your device through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits.  We use information gathered through analytics tools that utilize cookies to aggregate anonymized user information to help us better design our Sites, and to enhance the functionality you enjoy as you navigate between our digital services.

We also may use cookies to match the right people with the right message you see on our Services or on third-party sites in conjunction with third-party advertising companies.

By using our site or allowing your browser to “accept cookies”, you consent to use of cookies with respect to your device.

For more information about how we use cookies read our [Cookie Policy,](http://www.pennwell.com/index/cookie-policy.html) and see our [Manage Your Cookie Settings](http://www.pennwell.com/index/manage-cookies.html) page to manage your cookie preferences

PennWell does provide your personally identifiable information to (i) trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential, and (ii) trusted third parties with whom PennWell contracts with to provide you services and products whereby, in such instances, notice will be provided to you before such services or products are purchased. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

In addition to providing you with our own content and content that we license, we offer you the opportunity to access others’ branded content and expertise. When you choose to take advantage of that content and expertise, you choose to have your name and contact details transferred directly to that other company or companies.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ or the Network Advertising Initiative ([www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)).

We offer online communities, websites, and mobile applications that allow you to publish content. We will publish the user name that you provide when you comment or publish other content. Privacy controls may be provided to allow you to manage your profile on these sites and applications. It is your responsibility as a professional to locate, understand, and utilize these privacy controls.

We reserve the right to use or disclose PII in connection with: (i) legal proceedings or preparations therefore; (ii) to respond to judicial or other government process such as court orders, subpoenas, requests for discovery and similar litigation relation requirements; (iii) to provide information to law enforcement agencies or for an investigation on a matter related to public safety; and (iv) in general to comply with applicable laws, government requests and court orders.  We may elect to make these disclosures even if we have not received a subpoena, if we believe in good faith that we have a legal obligation to do so, or if we believe that our failure to do so may result in liability to us, or a violation of law.

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act.  Protecting consumer privacy is important to PennWell. 

PennWell complies with the _EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield  Frameworks_ as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the  _European Union and Switzerland_  to the United States. PennWell has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. We are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and other United States governmental agencies.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://na01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.privacyshield.gov%2F&data=02%7C01%7CDWarren%40Pennwell.com%7C1eeb3cb085e74982c40e08d4f6c8ee3a%7C5bbf75da8a3f493c8343e6cd0cb0e070%7C0%7C0%7C636404790247847523&sdata=dsDOQV%2FCXxS%2FvlBL%2FsO7pUZQouDm3YuPdTUAl6fiy58%3D&reserved=0).

### Accountability For Onward Transfer

We endeavor to enter into contracts with third-party data controllers, which provide (i) that data subject to the Privacy Shield may only be processed for limited and specified purposes consistent with the consent provided by the individual; and (ii) that the recipient will provide the same level of protection as the Principles and will notify us if it makes a determination that it can no longer meet this obligation and that if such a determination is made, the third-party controller will cease processing or will take other reasonable and appropriate steps to remediate.

We transfer personal data to a third party acting as an agent under the following conditions: (i) for limited and specified purposes; (ii) we ascertain that the agent is obligated to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Principles; (iii) we take reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure that the agent effectively processes the personal information transferred in a manner consistent with the organization’s obligations under the Principles; (iv) we require the agent to notify the us if it makes a determination that it can no longer meet its obligation to provide the same level of protection as is required by the Principles; (v) we will, upon notice, take reasonable and appropriate steps to stop and remediate unauthorized processing; and (vi) we will provide a summary or a representative copy of the relevant privacy provisions of our contract with that agent to the U.S. Department of Commerce (the “ **Department** “) upon request. We remain potentially liable if an agent that we engage to assist us does so in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles.

We commit to cooperate with EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) and comply with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU in the context of the employment relationship, as well as non-human resources data transferred from the EU. Specifically, we commit to cooperate with the DPAs, including but not limited to cooperating with the DPAs in the investigation and resolution of complaints brought under the Privacy Shield and complying with any advice given by the DPAs where the DPAs take the view that we need to take specific action to comply with the Principles, including remedial or compensatory measures for the benefit of individuals affected by any non-compliance with the Principles, and we further agree to provide the DPAs with written confirmation that such action has been taken.

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act) and children under the age of 13 are not eligible to use the services of this site. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years of age or older.

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at [http://www.pennwell.com/index/terms-and-conditions.html](http://www.pennwell.com/content/pw/en/index/terms-and-conditions.html)

By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy.

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

Under the law of some countries, you may have the right to access the information PennWell holds about you, correct mistakes in that information, and to delete personal information. If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or request deletion on our site by submitting your request via [this form](http://www.pennwell.com/content/pw/en/index/customer-service-form.html) to our customer service team.  We will respond to requests within 30 days. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy or complaints about our websites, you may contact us using the information below.

1421 S. Sheridan  
Tulsa, OK 74112  
United States  
Website:  [www.pennwell.com](http://www.pennwell.com/)  
Email:  [Complete Form](http://www.pennwell.com/content/pw/en/contact.html)  
Phone:  800-331-4463

As part of the Privacy Shield self-certification, the DMA acts as PennWell’s dispute resolution mediator.  We have selected the DMA, as the independent dispute resolution body (the “Arbiter“) designated to address your complaints and provide appropriate recourse to you free of charge.  The DMA is an alternative dispute resolution provider based in the United States.  An individual who decides to invoke this arbitration option must first, prior to initiating an arbitration claim, raise the claimed violation directly with us and afford us an opportunity to resolve the issue within the timeframe set forth in the Principles. If you have exhausted all other means to resolve your concern regarding a potential violation of our obligations under the Principles, you may invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel. For additional information about the arbitration process please visit the Privacy Shield website at [www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/);

If you are a European consumer and wish to gain access to the data that PennWell controls about you, or if you wish to have your data corrected or deleted, please click on the following link to our request form.
